Hey guys, thanks so much for joining
this video. In today's class, I'm going
to show you how to make a bolo style
necklace. And um the one that I'm
wearing right now is our prototype. So,
it's the one that I kind of put together
just to see how it would look. And I
have some ideas for a respin of a second
version where the tassel is just a
little bit longer. Um but this is a
total, you know, make it your own
design. Like you can totally change this
up. It can be different lengths,
different styles. Um but really what I
want to teach you today is the recipe
for how to create it. So, creating it is
super easy. It's a series of stringing
um using a beading wire. I'm going to be
using fine beading wire. And then uh
some 2x2 crimps. Um in a couple places I
added some crimp covers, but they're not
required. And you could always do the
magic crimper if that's something that
you do.
And then right at the end,
we're going to do some beautiful
earrings. And these earrings are really
easy to make and they use the same
concept as our bolo necklace
um with some cool draping and looping of
the beading wire to really get your
style on. And I'll show you all the
beads I've used, which are of course
from August Sam's Bead Box uh Mojave
Desert.
So, here on the mat, I have an
assortment of the beads that I used in
both of the lariat and the earrings.
And of the beautiful findings from the
box for the lariat we're going to be
using
this gorgeous piece right here. It's one
of my favorites. It's going to have a
connection top and bottom so we can use
it as part of our our style to do the
dangle.
And so that's how I used it here but
keep in mind you could also pull in the
flowers. You could pull in this gorgeous
horse charm. Um save this one I have a
bracelet project we're doing later in a
future class.
Um and so we did we did a whole unboxing
on August um
12th and I so you go back and watch that
to see the whole box but what I have out
here is a selection a few of the items
are not present on the mat cuz we don't
need them for this current project but
there's um you know a whole bunch of
other beautiful things from the box that
we use in other projects. But these are
the ones that I primarily drew from to
do the bolo necklace and the earrings.
So there's a lot of beautiful strands.
Um I went crazy and just did some
stringing.
Just going through and making a really
beautiful necklace. That's done at the
end but what we're going to do is step
one
is what I what I found worked really
beautifully
is that um let me bring these over here
so those are included as well.
I need a little ring to kind of do the
suspension. There's a couple of
different ways you can do this depending
on what beads you choose for it. I chose
these
with the seed beads.
And I think that's a really good combo
but the reason that I went with those is
they made a nice easy circle.
Keep in mind some of these other beads
like these we know these work because
they're the ones that are used in the
earrings. You could make the center link
with a lot of other choices here. So you
can get creative but the basic structure
I'll just demo with the beads I used in
the prototype. So I'm going to clear the
mat just really quick
and demonstrate making
the focal ring.
So, you just need a handful of seed
beads and it doesn't matter which colors
you choose. You can use any colors you
want.
And then, I'm going to be using
approximately five of these.
But, this is again not set in stone. You
can use as few or as many as you can get
a circle to form, then you've got it.
And then, the way we join the beading
wire to it is in between each of the
beads. So, it's really, really easy to
do. Um I made the ring first. Let me
just talk a little bit about like
options cuz I think there's there's more
than one way you could do this. But, the
basic recipe is I created this ring and
then I joined my dangles and my necklace
chains to it. If you want to make your
necklace chains and dangle first and
then join them to the ring, that's an
option. Um or you can join your strands
to the ring, which is what I actually
did here cuz I wasn't sure what my links
were yet and I wanted to be able to hold
it up and play with it as I worked. So,
that's why I did it in that order, but
that order is not required.
Um I'm going to be using some beading
wire from Soft Flex.
I have fine beading wire and you can use
any color you like. I I happen to just
have a lot of the copper color, uh but
you could use bone and the other color
that came in our trio. Those would be
really beautiful options, too.
So, you only need a little bit of
beading wire here.
And I can't remember how much I cut, but
I did it probably about a little over
what I want my ring to be.
So, um I'll get you a measurement
though, just to just to help out with
that.
I like to have room to maneuver, so I go
a little over. But, I cut cut a little
cut about 6 in and you should be fine.
And then, go ahead and string on a bead.
And again, any colors you would like.
I think I'm going to go with this
lighter brown.
Okay.
And
you'll have that.
Ain't it beautiful?
We need a crimp bead.
So, what I have here is a copper 2 by 2
crimp.
And I'm going to bring the beading wire
through it.
And the other side through it in the
opposite direction.
And when you get close to where it's
pulled tight, I would suggest if you
can,
the cool thing about working with fine
is you can perhaps go around again. And
this will just make your ring really,
really strong.
Oops, I skipped a seed bead there.
See, see, I'm just going around again.
And only because this particular ring
here is going to be supporting a lot of
the weight of my design.
We don't have to do this on the
earrings. The earrings are really light.
But on this one, I think it's
really cool and it works out really
nicely.
All right. So, I got all the way around.
Again, this was about a little over 6 in
of beading wire that I started with.
And then we're going to go through the
crimp one more time.
And you may or may not be able to get
through the bead again. But one of the
reason I chose these beads was I noticed
that they had a very generous hole
diameter and it worked out very nicely
for me.
And on this side, I can't even get it
through on that side as well.
So, that's a lot of passes through them.
But look how strong.
So, now you have this gorgeous
component. And think of the
possibilities of a component like this,
the things you could do in jewelry and,
you know, making in general. There's a
lot of possibility there.
So, here's my crimp tool.
And I'm going to go ahead and just
crimp here.
And crimp here.
I'm not going to put a crimp cover on
this component because I'm going to be
having um beading wire going over it.
And so, it doesn't really have room. Uh
but later when we do work on the rest of
the design, I will show you where I did
add crimp covers.
On this one, don't sweat that. We don't
need it.
And now I'm just trimming the beading
wire.
As close as I can. And one of the
reasons I go through the bead
is you get a really nice clean look
there. See how nice that is? It's really
solid. And then my beading wire doesn't
show next to it. It's really cool. Okay,
so let's go ahead and get our next step
onto the mat.
So, let's make the tassel next. The
reason I like to make the tassel next is
that at that point you'll have it ready
to test, try on, and test as you make
your chain in the final step. So, that's
This is kind of the order I did it in.
Um
but again, like I was saying in the
beginning, you could always do different
order. But so, this is how to make the
little decorative tassels. And creative
on this, go crazy. Do whatever you want
to do. Um mine originally, let me hold
it up really quick. Looks like that. But
I might do something a little longer for
this one just for more dramatic effect.
Um but you can really go wild and make
something cute.
So, you're going to need another
another bit of beading wire and crimps.
But first, before we get there, let's
create the little bottom dangles. So,
you may need three or even four. In my
case, I used four. Um
I only have head pins. If you have eye
pins, um bring two of those out and two
head pins out, but I'm just going to
make two of these into an eye pin.
You're going to need a jump ring, which
is going to be the little thing that
holds all the little tassel together.
And the little tassel is going to go at
the bottom of your longhorn pendant.
So, any beads you like. What I did for
mine, and what I kind of really want to
do again cuz I think it looks really
cute, was I like the look
of these beautiful multi multi melon
color melons with these beautiful bell
flowers on top.
I thought they looked really cute. Let
me show you.
And then I also like the look of the
bicones with the bell flowers. So, the
bicones are these the strand here.
It's really pretty. And then above that,
I've got just a beautiful suspension of
the larger bell flower. And then I use
the pinch bead. Now, my goal here is to
have a little longer tassel happening,
so I might go a little little more extra
for this one, but let's start with my
favorite.
And we'll go with one of those.
And then we need to free some of these.
Some beautiful things happening here.
Grab a couple of those.
All right.
So, string on your
melon bead and one of the
bell flowers.
And I'm going to grab some round nose
pliers and just do a nice gentle wrapped
loop on the top.
There's one.
So, so far I have that.
And then I like to get out my
chain nose.
And then I use some square nose to hold.
And you can either use your hand or use
a chain nose plier. I have some pretty
strong head pins here, so I'm going to
go around with my tools.
And it'll either be able to get two,
maybe three coils
um around before you need to trim it.
Um that.
This is going to be something that um
you see a lot in your design because
you're going to have it hanging on the
front of the necklace. It's a little
fidget piece that you'll probably handle
a lot when you're wearing it. Just a
I do that a lot with my jewelry, and so
I'm going to take extra care and time
with these wraps cuz they're going to be
something I look at a lot and I want to
be proud of them.
So, there's one.
Feel free to make one more or something
different. Other options that are really
great for suspension are flowers,
are these beautiful chevron leaves.
These are really gorgeous options. Some
of the other beads would work. So, go to
town. Go ahead and make
um another one like
So, I have these beauties, and now I'm
going to go ahead and make some eye pins
out of these. So, start with the um And
for for your eye pins, feel free to just
use round nose pliers, but I have a
preference for using my bell formers.
Just so that my eye pins are the same
size.
And I'm going to make a loop here at the
bottom.
And then here at the top, I will need to
trim off the top of my head pin.
And what do I want to use as a dangle?
So, bringing back the other piece just
real quick for reference. What I did
over there was
a larger bell flower, and then
I'm thinking I might do the same thing
for the larger one of these or maybe the
smaller one or some
asymmetry here.
And so if you're doing that, your bell
flower is going to hang a little bit
like this. So if you want, go ahead and
open
that loop
and attach whichever dangle you are
using to that.
I'm just going to go like that.
See? Pretty cool. You can do anything
you like here. This is really freestyle.
Gorgeous jewelry. And then back to
making.
You could either do a
wrapped loop here at the top.
I'm choosing a wrapped loop because it's
going to look
like a little branch, but you could
always do a
simple loop here, too.
But I think what I'm kind of doing is
I'm matching
the wrapped loop here at the bottom
with the wrapped loop here on the top.
And don't sweat it if you're being a
little perfectionist about it like me.
It's okay.
This is going to be something that is
the
the very um
the very spotlight of your necklace.
And so I'm going to do the same thing
with this one, but I'm going to make
this one a little longer.
So I made you two beads. Now on my
original I only had one, but I feel like
I want to change it up. So let's do
um
Let's do this. Let's do a flower.
So this flower will be here.
And then I need something that'll make
this space and so it's going to be one
of my larger beads.
Actually think one of these might work.
Um or
let's just see.
So, I'm thinking
this one will be on the jump ring like
that.
And then I can get away with another
bead really close to the top, but then I
need a little spacing. So, what if we
did one of these gorgeous ones?
Now, if you're doing the loom project
with me on the
29th, you're going to want to save
a fair amount of these. I don't use all
of them in the loom bracelet design, but
I do use quite a few. So, go sparingly
on those ones.
But, don't be afraid to use a little bit
of them.
What do you think of that as a dangle?
Something a little different. So, I'm
going to put that together you making
a series of connections with head pin
eye pin.
So, here's my little dangle. I went a
little crazy and made them a little
bigger than last time, and I'm really
happy with how they look. But, keep in
mind this is all just style. Whatever
you think will look really cute. Our
goal is to kind of simulate the look of
a bolo. So, bolo has, you know, it's a
tie, but it has two long strands coming
out from a center, right? And so, that's
where I'm
where I'm trying to take these. Let me
just close that a little better.
Give me that one. Just say it seems to
appear to be a little bit open.
There we go.
And we'll just get that onto our jump
ring.
There's one.
And two.
Now, I'm going to take the
beautiful
long horn pendant.
And as best I can, I'm going to try to
close this jump ring.
The pendant's pretty big, so you might
find that
a round jump ring might do better, but I
only had these in the color I wanted.
This was the size jump ring I had.
And I was able to get it to close. I
just had to be a little careful with it.
So, you'll have a little easier time
with that without an oval jump ring, but
it worked for me.
What do you guys think? Do you like it?
I might take this bead out.
So, let me show you my original.
It's a little simpler.
So, whichever you like. Um
real quick, I'm just going to remove
this one and save this link for
something else. This is a little too
big.
I think that's good.
So, yeah, any kind of little beautiful
drops, when you're wearing it, they're
going to kind of hang on top of each
other. Let me show you how they suspend.
See how they kind of go like that? So,
you're going to get a really cool little
look.
But, feel free to play with the height
of that. Get it to look how you'd like
it, too. And then, just here's another
little side-by-side.
So, that's the little focal that'll be
at the bottom of one of the little bolo
ties.
So, once you've got that done,
um what we're going to do next is the
section here.
So, we're going to create a series of
little bolo tie lengths that are made on
beading wire with crimps. And in this
case, I do have some crimp covers.
That's optional. So, all you need to do
is cut a length of beading wire
and create a little sampling
of strands of just random beads that you
like.
So, first I'm going to string on a
crimp.
And then, I'm going to attach that to
the top of my longhorn pendant. This
will be the
first of the two ties.
Give it some Give it some room to move.
You want it to dance a little bit.
Okay. Close your crimp.
If you have
an idea of the length you'd like it to
be,
just go ahead and lay it next to your
ring.
And I'm going to go for about 2 and 1/2
to 3 in.
So, my originals are
I did a very short little snippet of was
a little bit under two. So, I'm going to
go for something more like 2 and 1/2 to
3.
So, that I can get something
you know, that looks a little bit
different. So, 2 and 1/2 to 3 from here,
we'll cut it about the four. So, we have
room to do our folding and crimping.
And let's string on some gorgeous beads.
I had my heart set on seeing this one.
So, we'll put this one on.
And then I do love these brown beads.
These are so pretty.
Um let's get out some of these beautiful
bicones. Something that I think looks
really cool in jewelry is to do the
the high-low of a larger and a smaller
bead next to each other.
So, and then there's our pop of yellow,
which is really pretty. And then let's
let's go crazy. Let's do a big flower. I
liked the look of the big flower on my
last one. I'm feeling like I want to do
a chain of a plastic flower just for the
style.
We'll see.
Okay, bicone here.
And where are we on length? Let's go
with another bead. Let's put on one of
these gorgeous ones.
And I feel like I need one more.
Maybe we'll do one of these.
>> And then, let's do
a brown bicone.
Got it?
And
So, I want a bead that's not very um I
want one that's a little more flat
because of the way it's going to be
positioned.
So, you know, we could do another
flower.
A lot of flower in this strand, but
that's okay.
Okay.
Well, like I said, it is freestyle,
whatever you feel like doing. So, based
on that, what I think and this are all
like I said, this was the prototype.
I'd like to have the the metal be the
bottom. So, I'm going to cover my crimp
up here.
So, bring this around.
And let's go back through the flower.
And give ourselves Give it some room to
to sway, right?
In fact, if it can fit over the crimp,
that's even better.
All right.
Crimp covers if you like, otherwise no
worries.
And there's That's a longer bolo. See,
that's going to be cool. So, I'm just
going to do the same thing I did there
with um
make by making one more strand. And so,
here's what's going to happen with my
second one. My second one is on beading
wire. It's going to go from here
and it's going to go a little shorter.
I'll probably end it like maybe like
right here. Um and then at the bottom,
I'm going to need one more little
dangle. And I would invite you to use
one of your charms. You could do that,
which I didn't do on my first one, but
or or a big flower or in the case of
what I did here, create another little
dangle.
So, there's a really pretty idea, too.
So, try stuff and see what you get.
There we go. Perfect, right? This is
going to be cute. So, I've got my crimp
on already, and I'm going to place that
one just to the
if you're wearing it, it'll be
to your right.
Make sure that one stays a little over.
And again, we're going to put these both
over the crimp.
Cuz we're perfecting this design here
together.
Your beading wire may or may not fit
back through a pinch bead if you end
with a pinch bead at the top.
I'm a little determined, so I'm going to
see if I can get it to go through, but
let's see.
Do you guys like to go through a bead
after your crimps? I have a thing, it's
a habit. I I like to do that.
Here we go.
And I'd like it to still have that sway
and that movement.
So, we'll make that just a only a little
bit smaller. Okay.
So, just holding that up.
Happy with how that looks. Going to go
ahead and bravely crimp.
And we're good.
So, there is our sweet little bolo.
It's going to have a lot of motion
because I made it a lot longer this
time, but that is the look that I think
a bolo tie should have.
But, feel free to make any length that
you like.
So now, all we have to do is two
beautiful chains. The chains are
completely freestyle.
Uh and what you're going to do with the
chains is Well, I would suggest linking
um and holding it up to yourself, but
you could always just create the chain
separately and attach it.
Um but what we're going to do is we're
going to put each chain
one is going to go from here
and the other's going to go here.
So, you'll have
And when you put it on,
what you could do, and I'm just thinking
out loud, is you could link the beading
wire now so you could hold it up to
yourself and determine where you'd like
it to hang. But a bolo style like this
when I was looking at like images,
Rachel and I were thinking a longer
would be uh more reflective of the
style. So, I kind of tried to get it to
be a little longer where it would
suspend where it's not like a right on
the collarbone, you know, like you want
it a little a little bit lower.
Um so, that's where I'm going with my
necklace the chain links. But again,
like I said, you can really play with
it. And I think this one I went with
just chunky. I went with big big beads
and just kept going. You can do that or
if you want to do a pattern, feel free
to do a pattern. Um here off camera, I'm
going to just hit the pause button in my
recording and I'm going to start
stringing something I like and I'm going
to
put it together and hold it up to me and
we'll I'll I'll turn the camera back on
a couple times and show you my progress,
but I'm going to play with making a very
creative chain and any beads are welcome
to be part of that.
You guys, look at my beautiful chain
pattern.
I did not do a pattern on the first one
obviously, but I really wanted to do
something on this one that I thought I
thought this was cute and it has lots of
pops of color. Um oh, and I forgot my
pinch beads here, but this is going to
be really nice. So, I'm going to take
this out to a good length and then we're
going to just uh we're going to do some
test measures. So, like I'm going to put
it on
and see how I like it.
But basically, this is the pattern I
have going for this one.
So, I think I'm there on length. Um and
keep in mind you could always do what I
did on this design which was I had a
very long adjustable chain.
Um so, I'm going to go ahead and hold
this up. Let me switch my camera really
quick.
And apologies that bright light is here,
but um how I usually do this is I will
take and
decide where I want my pendant to
suspend. So, for me, I want it to go
like I think it's a good length that's
like right kind of at the center here.
And so, I think I'm there on length.
So, now now that I have a pattern, I can
copy my pattern. So, it's a little
easier if you do a pattern, but even if
you do rando, you can just hold it up.
So, I'm just going to crimp this end,
and I'm going to put a lobster claw on
one side.
So, you can see this side of the chain
is all attached. I've got my lobster
claw here. This side, I'm going to go
ahead and put my crimp on.
Another strand of beading wire. Uh I'm
still on the spool right now. I haven't
quite measured yet. I'm going to show
you how to measure that,
but I'm still still on my spool.
And I'm going to bring the
I've got this on its reverse side right
now. I'm going to bring this strand
to be right here.
So, bring it on
and under.
And then I'm just going to slide that
down.
All right. So, um what I want to do now
is I do have to cut free from the spool
so I can string.
So, just to give you a heads-up on how
to measure,
just go ahead and pull
like this, see, along your chain.
And you know you're going to want to
match your pattern.
And then when you reach where you're
going to have your crimp, right here,
give yourself some extra length.
And I'm usually pretty generous with it
cuz I don't like to have to fumble
with folding it and
so, I give myself an extra inch or two.
All right. So, what I'm going to do now
is copy copy this strand onto this
beading wire.
So, here's my beautiful chain.
All finished up and it's nice cuz you
can match it like lay it next to side by
side. Make sure you get your you know,
your dimensions right, your colors
right. Things are looking okay to me.
Don't be afraid to check it a few times
though cuz so many times you guys I've
made these and
and sometimes I spot errors, but
they'll just look together.
Not that it would be the end of the
world, but you know how you know how I
am.
So, I want to be right. So, there we go.
And uh I just have some extender chain.
I like to put chain at the end of
necklaces so that it is customizable.
We'll go back through our green bead.
It's a nice bead to end with because it
has a really easy to get through hole.
And then
I'm going to just, you know, do the
thing I like to do where I give it some
wave, right? Make sure I'm getting the
tightness right.
Okay.
And we'll crimp here.
Trim.
And try.
Let's try it on. Let me show you on the
mat really quick. Just one more
glance at the gorgeousness.
And again, everything's going to spin a
little bit, but don't worry about that.
So, there's the bolo section. Starts
here with our little ring.
And then here's our gorgeous chain and
again, this time I did a pattern.
It's going to achieve a little different
look.
All right. So,
that's perfect.
The length is exactly where I wanted it.
So, I was going for and let me make the
light a little better for you guys to
see. I was going for the length to be
not collar. So, I sometimes you see with
bolos if a guys like wearing it with
like a like a button tie shirt, they
might scrunch it up, but I wanted for
this necklace to be more feminine and so
it would be hanging down. But, keep in
mind that can you can, if you want to,
make this any length based on just
change the length of your chain here.
And then, you can make these ties any
length. And so, as you saw it maybe
comparison from the other one to this
one, I like I vastly prefer the longer
ties. So, I think it just gives it more
symmetry. Like, it kind of balances it,
right?
Uh but, I can always pop the other one
on just so you can see
the difference if you make your dangles
different lengths. So, here was the
prototype. The one that we showed in the
beginning.
And on that one, I'm going to hook it to
the same
spot on my chain here.
And on that one, we got
I achieved the same length here,
but you see the ties seem a little bit
shorter. And so,
I don't know. I feel like
I preferred
the longer ones. What do you guys think?
Anyway, that's the whole idea. And both
of them next to each other.
See if I can hold them up.
They're pretty cute. Oh, my goodness.
So, yeah. Um let's make a matching pair
of earrings.
So, this is a very cute technique that
you can try. We'll create using the same
kind of, you know, beading wire looping
that we've been using on lately. Um
you're going to need to create just a
couple little components. So,
you need two eye pins and two head pins.
Or, if you only have head pins, just
grab four and we will make our own.
You could also use craft wire here if
you want.
I like the head pins cuz they tend to be
a little more um
you know, they're hardened wire, so they
tend to be easier to do a simple loop
with. And I like the look of a simple
loop on this particular component. So,
I'm going to use these gorgeous chevron
leaves. It's one of my favorite beads in
the collection. Going to need four of
them.
And start by creating
uh two dangles. You twist two of each
together.
And all I did there was I headpin
folded it
trimmed to a quarter inch
roughly.
And then I do like to
use the bail former
to bring that right up.
So, make one of those.
And same thing, we're going to make a
eye pin with another headpin.
And get that one.
Trim the top off if you need to.
And another chevron leaf.
And this time I'm going to bend this
forward.
Trim to a quarter inch.
And I'm going to use the bail formers
again.
So, there we have
cute dangle.
And one of these. So, make two more like
that.
And I'll do that here at the end. We'll
just keep going on this one.
Uh the next thing we're going to do is
we're going to need our beads. So, the
beads that I used, and again, any beads
you want for me, but I used were the
pinch beads
the cactus color melon beads, and then I
used some of those green beads that we
had out earlier.
Two for each earring.
They're just going to be there at the
top. For your beading wire, you're going
to need um you know, don't worry about
making it exact. Just go for
I think in this case it was
What I usually do is measure like that
and then we'll just trip uh quadruple
it. So, 1 2 3 4. I'm going to go right
about there. I eyeball measurements a
lot, but let me get you a measurement.
Go for 10 in
and that's probably too much, but it's
okay.
You'll make it.
I'm going to start with a crimp bead.
And you'll need two for each earring.
Two crimp beads for each earring.
And bring that on.
And bring that to about the midpoint.
And then if you would like,
you can crimp it there. And that is what
I did on mine because I wanted to hold
my midpoint
and I didn't want it to wiggle while I
was working.
So, got my midpoint marked.
And I just went ahead and crimped it.
Again, that's optional if you want to.
Bring on the dangle. That is a
headpin one.
And on either side you're going to put a
pinch bead.
So, we'll put a pinch bead here.
And then on the other side I'm going to
put a pinch bead on.
So, you're going to get that.
Sorry, if I got Do you close there?
Okay. So, um
And now for what I call the cactus
melons. These are so pretty. I think in
this box, it's really hard to choose a
favorite bead, but if I was pressed to
do so, uh this is my favorite my
favorite one.
And I said that about the leaves, too.
So, you guys see my my dilemma, but oh
my gosh, look at that.
Make sure you grab the extras before me.
I can't be trusted. I'll buy them all.
They're so cute. So, what I'm doing here
is um
cactus bead,
and then we're going to follow that with
another pinch bead.
Same thing on each side.
And now we need two more of the cactus
beads.
One on each side.
There's one.
And one.
And one more pinch bead. Okay. On the
pinch bead,
cross the cross the wire through it.
And this is your chance to get that
tight.
And once you've got that as you like it,
follow up with two more cactus beads.
Here's one on one side.
One on the other.
We need two pinch beads, one on each
side.
And then I just liked how this looked.
This is optional if you like it, but I
like the look of the green.
And then we're going to need
another crimp.
And you you can't put the dangle on this
one yet, because what we're going to
need to do is crimp it, so
that's why we did simple loops so we can
open them.
Bring your beading wire through the
green bead.
And then let's pull and tighten all of
that.
And one thing that's going to happen is
you're going to have a lot of space
here.
You're going to have to kind of
encourage
each side
to consume that space.
And then it is a little tricky. I keep
having one side and tighten the other.
So roughly like that.
And then when you get your crimp tool in
there, you might have to tighten it
again. And there is one way to do this.
Bite one side.
And if you do that, I just usually
literally just bite that side and then
pull that side. I know it's
it's a little bit
um it's like I can't think of a word.
Bohemian, I guess.
There we go. Okay.
But it works and if it works, it works,
right?
And that's another reason to make your
loops a little longer.
And there we go. So all we have to do
now is I'm going to grab an ear wire.
There's this one here.
And open that ear wire at the end. I'll
open this one first.
So finding the open side of my simple
loop.
Close that.
And then often I'll kind of like line
them up. One thing I want to mention
here is you're going to want to have
these be perpendicular to each other. So
you see how right now they're parallel.
Just turn it like that.
So that your loop that your wire is
going on
is facing that way.
See? So it looks like that. And now we
get our ear wire going.
We'll put
that on this way.
Simple easy pair of earrings. Little
cactus loops.
I need to make the matching pair for the
third one there, but there they are. And
so you can really make a lot of
different earrings in this style using
different beads.
So here's the earrings.
They look nice, right? They're really
fun. Neat little style.
They'll move around on you a little bit
with the spinning of those little cactus
leaves or with those forgive me, they
are the chevron leaves, but I keep
calling them cactus leaves cuz that's
how they look to me. And then again,
once again, this is the bolo
necklace, bolo tie necklace. And all
these, you know, ideas can be of course
customized into something that you think
is really cool.
Um but I really think these came out
perfect for what I was going for. So
yeah.
Earrings one more time and a big thank
you. I love the Mojave Desert Box, this
one, you know, near and dear to my
heart. I have gotten to do
four boxes now Sam's Bead Shop and this
one I like every time I think we can't
top the last one. Um even though they're
all great, like I still like wow,
there's just things we can do that are
so cool. So this one I love because I
did grow up in the area and I like the
colors and it brings back a lot of
memories for me. I also just really love
the wanderer bohemian style. Like before
we when we were designing this, we kind
of thought like oh, we're going to call
it the wandering lariat cuz it's got all
these like just kind of lost in the
desert finds, you know, going along. But
um then it it just looks so much like a
bolo tie that that's what popped out. So
you can not go wrong. You're going to
get something you love with every could
just string these and you'll have
something so happy and beautiful. So, I
can't wait to see what you create. Post
it in Gem Chat so I can see. And um
please join me for the next class. The
next class is going to be another pair
of earrings and a loom project. I'm
going to show you really quick.
So, if you
felt like these earrings are a little
too sedated,
we're going to go to town on earrings.
Check these out. These are wild. These
are big and but they're light because
it's a wooden component. You could turn
this into a pendant if this is uh
something that you think would look good
as a pendant, too. Um there's three of
them in your box, so you can make a
pendant and a matching pair of earrings.
Um but those are going to be really,
really fun. And last but not least, I
have a loom project for you that I'm
going to be teaching.
And this one, we're going to do some
macrame at the end to create a little
closure.
And the way that this closure works is
you get a sort of um looped appearance
here. So, let me hold it up closer so
you can see how square knotted. And then
on one side you have these
beads that are like your button.
And so, that's going to be really fun.
We'll do that together. I do have one
more project in work, which is going to
be a macrame bracelet that features that
little bracelet component.
And I just had it out and I set it down
a while but do you remember the one? Oh,
here it is. Okay, so this one.
Um you'll have seen this if you watched
the unboxing cuz I'll have it done by
then. But I'm filming this before I've
finished this one, so I don't have it to
hold up now, but I will by then.
So, you'll know what I've what I've got
that done. And then guess what I didn't
use yet? These beautifuls.
I need to do something with these. Maybe
another pair of earrings. Maybe I don't
I don't know. So, I can't wait to see
what you make and I'll catch you for the
next one. Bye for now.
>> Mhm.